それは 使用している枕から➡
なんか
おっさんのにおい すんぞ！
(土方)ｵﾒｴのにおいだっつうの｡
はい すばり答えましょう｡
人は いつから
おっさんになるのですか？｣
お父さんと同じにおいが
するようになったらです｡
ということで 関係ないけど
大西！ 立ってなさい｡
(近藤)おい！
誰だ ｵﾚの枕 勝手に使ったの！
(銀時)え～
千葉県 名無しさんからの質問｡
皆さんも 枕のにおいには
常に 注意を払ってください｡
｢『銀魂』内では 長谷川 近藤が
おっさん呼ばわりされますが➡
歳の近い 銀さん 土方は
おっさん呼ばわりされません｡
[Teach me!! Ginpachi Sensei!]
Teach me!!
Ginpachi Sensei!
[Question Corner]
[Ginpachi Sakata]
Let's see... This question comes from Anonymous-san of Chiba prefecture.
In "Gin Tama," Hasegawa and Kondo are called "ossan."
But Gin-san and Hijikata, who are nearly the same age, aren't middle-aged.
[Ossan = a middle-aged man in Kansai dialect, but recently has become slang to mean the same thing]
So, just when do guys start being called an "ossan"?
Yes, let me answer that.
It's when the pillow you're using starts to smell like your father.
Hey, who's been using my pillow without my permission?! It smells like an "ossan."
That's what you smell like, idiot.
Everyone, please be careful of how your pillow smells.
And now on a totally unrelated note... Onishi! Keep standing!
[Odd Jobs Gin]
[A gift from Tatsuma Sakamoto to apologize for destroying Odd Jobs]
[Unkei & Kaikei, Delivery Carpenters from space]
＜新八:事故で 記憶をなくした
銀さんと➡
With Gin-san losing his memory in an accident and
坂本さんの宇宙船による
万事屋の崩壊で➡
Sakamoto's spaceship destroying the Odd Jobs,
ﾎﾞｸらは 名実ともに
ﾊﾞﾗﾊﾞﾗになってしまった＞
we were, in name and reality, all broken up.
(銀時たち)うわぁっ！
(土方)いけぇっ！
Go!
木刀 持ってきたろうな？
あっ… はい！
You brought my wooden sword, right?
Huh? Oh... Yes.
Hey, Boss.
工場長 すんません
今日で 辞めさせてもらいま～す！
Sorry, but I'm handing in my resignation.
銀さん！
銀ちゃん！
G-Gin-chan!!
♪♪～
＜ こうして
銀さんの記憶は戻った｡
And that was how Gin-san's memory was restored.
もう１つのほうは
まだ 壊れたままだけど＞
Although the other thing is still broken.
(ﾄﾝｶﾁの音)
[Odd Jobs Gin]
(神楽)うおぁ～っ！ うりゃあっ!!
Hey, Gin-san.
ねぇ 銀さん｡
あ？
ﾎﾞｸら
万事屋を直してるんですよね？
We're trying to fix Odd Jobs, right?
(神楽)うおりゃ～！
All I hear are the sounds of fingers and the house being destroyed.
指と家を破壊する音ばかり
聞こえてくるんですけど｡
創造と破壊は
表裏一体だよ 新八君｡
Creation and destruction are two sides of the same coin, Shinpachi-kun.
いつまでたっても
創造が始まらないんですけど｡
Yeah, but when are we gonna flip the coin?
やっぱ ﾑﾘだ｡ 素人が
大工なんて できるわけない｡
I knew it. This is hopeless. You should never let amateurs do carpentry.
ﾊﾞｶ野郎｡
お前 最近の大工のなかには➡
You idiot! Professionals rip you off and do lousy work anyway.
欠陥住宅とか造ってる
ﾛｸでもねえﾔﾂだっているんだぞ｡
At least they get something done, you idiot.
欠陥人間が造るよりﾏｼだ ﾊﾞｶ野郎｡
Can't help it. We don't have the money to hire a carpenter.
しかたねえだろ
大工 雇うにも 金がねえんだよ｡
それとも なにか？ ばばあに
追い出されてもいいのか？
Or what? You want the old hag to kick us out?
Besides, if you call yourself an "Odd Jobs" man,
だいたい ﾃﾒｴらも
万事屋の端くれなら➡
you should be able to fix something like this easily. Idiot...
こんくらい 器用に直せ ﾊﾞｶ…
うおぉ～っ!!
Gin-chan, desperate times call for desperate measures!
銀ちゃん！
こうなったら これよ！
No...wait...Kagura-chan.
いや！
ちょっ 待って 神楽ちゃん！
うりゃあ～っ！
うわっ うっ… うわぁっ！
うわぁ！
(神楽)あぁっ！
うわぁ～っ！
うぉ～っ！
やめろって！
Yeow, stop!!
なんか この子 反抗期みたいよ！
I can't. This kid is rebelling!
うわぁっ！
ﾊﾞｶ！
その暴れん坊将軍 止めろ～い!!
You idiot! Stop that "Bold Shogun"!
神楽ちゃん ﾎﾞｸら 死ぬ！
ﾏｼﾞで 死ぬ！
Kagura-chan, we're gonna die! Seriously, we're gonna die!
ｽｲｯﾁ ｽｲｯﾁ！ 早く止めて!!
(神楽)ﾀﾞﾒよ！
The switch, the switch! Turn it off!
I can't! I've never dealt with a rebellious kid before!
私 反抗期の子 扱うの
初めてね！
If you don't know how to use it, then don't even try!
扱い方 わかんねえなら
最初から使うな～！
ぐはっ！
ひゃあ～っ!!
Take this!
この～っ!!
(神楽/新八)うわぁ～っ!!
うほっ！ うわっ！
ｸｿｯ！
ｸｿじゃないから！
Dammit!
What do you mean, dammit?!
ｱﾝﾀ ﾎﾞｸを壊して どうすんのさ！
Why are you trying to destroy me?
Don't worry.
心配するな｡
人は 古い自分を壊して➡
People destroy their old selves so they can embark on a journey to find their new selves.
新しい自分探しの旅へ出るんだ｡
Embarking, my ass!
出るかぁ！ これじゃ
違う世界に旅立つわ ﾎﾞｹｪ!!
You were about to send me off to another world, you moron!
(衝撃音)
Kagura, don't move!
神楽～ じっとしてろ!!
くるね 銀ちゃん！
I got it, Gin-chan.
(神楽/銀時)うらぁ～っ!!
お～し 止まったぞ｡
Okay, it stopped.
一件落着ね｡
いや 落着してないから！
Case closed.
What do you mean, "case closed"?! This place looks worse than before.
前より
ひどくなってるから これ！
Ding dong.
(宅配便屋)ﾋﾟﾝﾎﾟｰﾝ｡
ﾋﾟﾝﾎﾟｰﾝ｡
すみません お届け物で～す｡
Ding dong.
Excuse me, I have a delivery for you.
"Mistaking Someone's Name Is Rude!"
(坂本)｢金時君 長らく
連絡をとってませんでしたが➡
Dear Kintoki-kun, we haven't kept in touch for a while, but how are you doing?
いかが お過ごしでしょうか？
I'm fine as usual, flying all over the universe.
ﾎﾞｸのほうは 相変わらず➡
宇宙を 縦横無尽に
飛び回っております｡
Space is truly a great place.
やっぱり 宇宙は いいです｡
The other day, I had an opportunity to stop by Earth so I went to visit you.
先日 地球に寄ることがあったので
金時君に会いにいったのですが➡
But sadly, we missed each other.
どうにも すれ違いになり
残念です｡
Actually, I'm writing because there was something I wanted to tell you...
実は 今回 筆をとったのは➡
ｷﾐに 言いたいことが
あったからです｡
昔 ｷﾐは…｣
Way back then, you said...
((おい ｲﾊﾞﾗｷﾞ
また ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗ行ったらしいな｡
Hey, Ibaragi. I heard you went to a hostess club again. Next time, take me too.
今度 ｵﾚも連れてけ))
That's what you said.
(坂本)｢と 言っていましたが➡
[IbaraKI]
But his name isn't Ibaragi! It's Ibaraki!
彼は ｲﾊﾞﾗｷﾞ君じゃなく ｲﾊﾞﾗｷ君です｡
I thought, why bring it up now?
今さらと思いましたが やっぱり➡
But it's just rude to get someone's name wrong.
人の名前とか間違えるのは
失礼だと思います｡
それじゃ 元気で 金時君｡
Well, take care of yourself, Kintoki-kun.
[But it's just rude to get someone's name wrong, Kintoki. Well, take care of yourself, Kintoki-kun.]
From Tatsuma Sakamoto.
坂本 辰馬｡
P.S. 家 壊して ごめんね｡
P.S. Sorry for destroying your house.
P.P.S...
P.S.の P.S.
Haven't you always wanted to use "P.S." every time you write a letter? (lol)
この P.S.って 手紙 書くと
使いたくなるね ｶｯｺ笑い｣
笑えるかぁ～！ ｶｯｺ怒り～!!
Who's laughing?
Jeez, the body of the letter and the "P.S." should be the other way around!
本文とP.S.が 逆！ これ!!
人の家 壊しといて
P.S.で 済ませやがって！
He destroys my house and all I get is a "P.S." apology?
Yeah, and he gets people's names wrong, too!
ﾃﾒｴも 人の名前 間違えてるしよ！
Even if P.S. means I wish for world peace, it's still unforgivable.
よしんば P.S.が
世界平和を願う意味だとしても➡
許せねえよな これは！
Birds of a feather flock together...
(神楽)類は友を呼ぶｱﾙ｡
友達じゃねえよ こんなん！
We don't flock together!
I hope he dies. I hope he suffers a slow painful death.
頼むから 死んでくんねえかな～｡
すごく苦しい死に方してほし～い｡
落ち着いてくださいよ 銀さん｡
手紙は あくまで ｵﾏｹですよ｡
Take it easy, Gin-san.
The letter is just something extra.
坂本さん
これを送りたかったんでしょ｡
What Sakamoto-san really wanted to send you is this, right?
What's in this box?
何ｱﾙか？ この荷物｡
I bet he sent you a spectacular apology gift for what he did.
きっと こっちに
お詫びの品とか入ってるんですよ｡
そういや ｱｲﾂって たしか
ﾎﾞﾝﾎﾞﾝだったなぁ…｡
Oh yeah, now that I think about it, he is Mr. Richie Rich...
(３人)金!?
Money?
What's this now?
んだよ～｡
おぉ！
ｱﾊｯ｡
All right, all right. Well, why didn't you say so in the first place, you little rascal.
ちょいちょい｡ そうなら そうと
早く言えっつうの おちゃめさん｡
I tell you...
これで やっと直せますね｡
That guy is more...
We can finally fix up the house now...
...of a rascal than me.
あ ﾎﾝﾄ｡
Hello.
(ｳﾝｹｲ)どうも｡
(ｶｲｹｲ)このたびは ﾃﾞﾘﾊﾞ…｡
Thank you for calling Por-
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)ぐほっ！
う～ん｡
あ～ これ 夢だな おい｡
Oh, this must be a dream. It's illogical. This can't be happening.
支離滅裂だもん｡ ありえねえもん｡
There were little old men in there. Little old men squished inside.
ちっちゃい おっさん 入ってたよ｡
ちっちゃい おっさんが
敷きつめられてたね｡
No, those were dolls, right? They're dolls. Let's take another look...
いやいや 今の 人形でしょ？
人形ですよ｡
もっかい 見てみましょう｡
夢だって｡
いいかげん 目を覚ませよ ｵﾚ｡
I'm telling you, it's a dream! Come on, that's enough, I gotta wake up now.
どうも｡
このたびは ﾃﾞﾘﾊﾞ…｡
Hello.
Thank you for calling Por-
といえ～っ!!
No way! It's a dream. A weird dream.
ｳｿｳｿ 夢だ 夢｡
We're being tormented by hallucinations of tiny bald men.
ちっちゃい おっさんの悪夢に
さいなまれてるんですよ｡
All right, we're done here. Let's meet back after we wake up.
じゃあ 解散！ 目 覚ましたら➡
もっかい ﾐｰﾃｨﾝｸﾞな｡
(新八/神楽)う～っす｡
Okay.
Hang on there!!
(ｳﾝｹｲ)待たんかい！
ﾃﾒｴら
人の話を最後まで聞け ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
You buttheads!
Listen till we're done talking, you morons!
We're supposed to say, "Thank you for using Portable Carpenters!" You idiots!
このたびは ｵﾒｴ
ﾃﾞﾘﾊﾞﾘｰ大工を ご利用いただき➡
ありがとうございますってんだよ
この野郎！
ﾃﾞﾘﾊﾞﾘｰ大工？
知らねえよ そんなもん｡
Portable Carpenters? I've never heard of such a thing.
I have no idea what that is, so go home.
このたびは
そんなもん知らねえから 帰れ｡
(ｳﾝｹｲ)なんだ その言い草は！
How dare you talk to us like that!
We came all the way from a distant planet to fix your house!
(ｶｲｹｲ)遠い星から わざわざ
家 直しにきてやったんだぞ！
もしかして あなたたち
坂本さんに頼まれて？
By any chance, did Sakamoto-san ask you to come?
That's right! When we get a call, we go! No matter how far!
そうでぃ！
ｵﾚたちは 依頼があれば➡
星をも またいで
家を建てにいく➡
Unkei! And...
ｳﾝｹｲ！ そして！
Kaikei!! We're the Portable Carpenters!
ｶｲｹｲ！ ﾃﾞﾘﾊﾞﾘｰ大工なんだよ！
ﾁｪﾝｼﾞで｡
(ｳﾝｹｲ)いや そんなのないから｡
Don't you have anyone...taller?
This isn't an escort service.
ﾃﾒｴら そんなﾅﾘで
何ができるってんだよ？
You buttheads, what can you do looking like that?
どうせ お菓子の家くれえしか
作れねえんだろう？
I bet you can only make houses out of candy.
Oh, but then again, it's candy. That's not so bad...
あ でも お菓子か…
お菓子なら いいかもな｡うん｡
聞いて驚くなよ！
ｵﾚたちはなぁ…➡
Don't be shocked, but...
江戸を国際都市へと変えた
文明開化の象徴…➡
Do you know the mighty Terminal building, the symbol of Japan's might, which made Edo an international city?
あの 天高くそびえる ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙの➡
That terminal... Inside there...
中にある 給湯室の おたまとか
引っかける あれ！
You know that cupboard for ladles in the kitchen?
We made those!
あれ 作ったんだぞ！
戸を閉めても➡
Even when you close the door, they don't come crashing down.
おたまとか
ｶﾞｼｬﾝと落ちねえんだぞ ｺﾗｧ！
甘えよ｡ ｵﾚなんか 牛乳ﾊﾟｯｸで
本棚作ったぞ ｺﾗｧ！
That's lame. I made a bookshelf out of milk cartons.
地球に 優しいぞ ｺﾗｧ！
And it's environmentally friendly.
So? You think something like that is going to save the Earth?
なんだと？
それくらいの優しさで➡
地球が救えると思ってるのか!?
Who cares about the Earth, it's more like we don't have money.
地球っていうか 金がねえんだよ！
家計は 苦しいんだよ！
Yeah, we've got a tight household budget!
ｱﾝﾀら 何の話してんの～!?
What the heck are you guys talking about?
どうせ これ以上
悪くなることなんて➡
It can't get any worse. Let's have them do it.
ないんですから
やってもらいましょうよ｡
Besides, it looks like Sakamoto-san already paid them.
お金のほうは 坂本さんが
払ってくれたみたいだし｡
う～ん…｡
Do you know this saying?
こんな言葉を知ってるか？
It's something a carpenter named Mokichi once said...
茂吉って大工が
言った言葉でよぉ｡
よくしゃべる職人に
ﾛｸなﾔﾂは いねえって…｡
"Craftsmen who talk a lot are never good."
口で語る術を 知らねえﾔﾂを
職人という｡
A good craftsman hardly even knows how to use his mouth.
He lets his hands do the talking.
ゆえに職人は 腕で語る｡
ｵﾒｴらは どっちのｸﾁだ？
Which kind are you guys?
(２人)うぅ～…｡
(物音)
What's all that racket?
(お登勢)なんだい？ 夜中に｡
やかましいね｡
(お登勢)ｱｲﾂらかい… ん？
Is it them... Hm?
That punk burns me up!
(ｳﾝｹｲ)若造がぁ～！
ﾅﾏ言いやがってぇ～!!
[Odd Jobs Gin
Otose Snack House]
(ｶｲｹｲ)宇宙一の大工の腕を
見せてやるぅ～！
We'll show him who the best carpenters in the universe are!
なんだい？ ｱｲﾂら？
Who the heck are those guys?
(神楽/新八)おぉ～｡
A-Amazing.
す… すごい｡
They fixed everything in just a day...
たった１日で 全部 直ってる！
♪♪～
(ｶｲｹｲ/ｳﾝｹｲ)ﾌﾝｯ！
Take a look. The interior's perfect too.
みさらせ！ 中も完璧だ｡
These are the skills of the best carpenters in the universe!
これが 宇宙一の大工の腕よ｡
Awesome! They really are skilled carpenters.
すごい！
ﾎﾝﾄに すご腕の大工だったんだ！
銀さん やりましたね！
これで 営業 再開できますよ！
Gin-san, isn't that terrific? We're back in business again.
うん…｡
Something's not right.
なんか 違えな｡
(ｶｲｹｲ/ｳﾝｹｲ)えっ!?
万事屋ってよぉ
こんなに寂しかったっけ？
I don't remember Odd Jobs being this bleak.
It's not our fault you can't afford furniture!
おい！ 変なｲﾁｬﾓﾝつけるなよ！
元の形は いじってねえぞ！
We haven't touched the original structure.
No, no, no...
いやいやいやいや…｡
It's not that.
そういうんじゃねえんだよ｡
なんか足りねえんだよ～ え～と｡
Something's missing. Um...
Oh, I know.
あっ そうだ！
(新八/ｶｲｹｲ/ｳﾝｹｲ)うん？ あ？
I thought it looked dreary...
なんか 寂しいと思ったら➡
ここに ｼｬﾝﾃﾞﾘｱが ねえんだよ！
The chandelier is gone!
Chandelier?
(２人)ｼｬﾝﾃﾞﾘｱ!?
ｼｬﾝﾃﾞﾘｱって何だよ？
What do you mean, "chandelier"?
この内装に
ｼｬﾝﾃﾞﾘｱって おかしくねえ!?
Wouldn't a chandelier look funny in a traditional Japanese interior?!
…ていうか
そんなもの ありましたっけ？
Come to think of it, did we have something like that?
I'm sure we did. You just never looked at the ceiling. You must've forgotten.
あったよ たしか…｡
ほら 意外に 天井って➡
見ねえじゃん｡
忘れてんだよ お前｡
そういえば あった気がするね｡
Now that you mention it, I remember there was one.
あと ３階につながる
階段は どうした？
And, what happened to the stairs to the third floor?
The third floor?
３階!?
そんなもの あったんすか？
We had that? I never heard about that!
聞いてないよ｡
あ～ お前らは 知らないけどね｡
Oh yeah, you guys may not know about it. It used to be above the dresser.
ﾀﾝｽの上のとこに あったんだよ｡
The third floor was for my JUMP collection.
３階は ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ倉庫なんだ｡
ﾏｼﾞっすか？
Are you serious?
あと 私の部屋！
Also, my room looks weird. It wasn't this small.
これ おかしいね！
こんな 狭くないね！
ﾊﾞｶにすんなよ！
30畳は あるはずね！
Don't mess with me. The floor was enough for 30 Tatami mats.
[Note: Tatami mats are units to measure floor space.]
(２人)30畳!?
Thirty mats?
(ｳﾝｹｲ)押し入れ 30畳!?
(ｶｲｹｲ)ﾘﾋﾞﾝｸﾞより 広いじゃん！
That closet was thirty mats?
That's bigger than the whole room!
神楽 ちょっと 30畳は
ﾑﾘがあるんじゃないのか？
Kagura, isn't that pushing it a bit much?
じゃあ 20畳に 譲歩してやるよ！
Okay, then I'll compromise at twenty mats.
聞いたことねえよ
そんな傲慢な譲歩！
I've never heard such an unreasonable compromise!
あと 厠｡
たしか ｼｬﾜｰﾄｲﾚ 付いてたな｡
Also, the toilet. I'm pretty sure there was a shower toilet in there.
[Note: A shower toilet is a toilet that has a retracting shower head offering "rinse" and "bidet" functions.]
Also the bathroom wall was all glass. It had a more erotic feel to it.
それと 風呂場は ｶﾞﾗｽ張りね｡
もっと ｴﾛい感じだったｱﾙ｡
Oh, I remember, too. And there was a karaoke machine in the living room.
あっ ﾎﾞｸも思い出しました｡
たしか 居間に
ｶﾗｵｹ 付いてましたよ｡
Hang on there. We never even touched the living room! That should be the way it was.
待てい！
そんな所 いじってねえぞ！
そのままのはずだ！
Have you ever heard this story?
こんな話を知ってるか？
(３人)ん？
…昔な➡
Long ago...
There were two carpenters who vied to be the most popular carpenters in Edo...
江戸の人気を
二分する大工がいた｡
１人は 長者の息子で
腕もいいが➡
One was a millionaire's son, who was skilled and also well off. His name was Gohei.
金回しもうまい 五兵衛｡
もう１人は 釘が打てりゃ➡
The other was odd and boasted that as long as he could drive a nail, he'd never want for food-Mokichi.
飯は いらねえと豪語する
変人 茂吉｡
茂吉は 立身出世なんざ
興味なしだったが➡
Mokichi had no interest in worldly success, but Gohei was different.
五兵衛は 違った｡
Every day, Gohei schemed to get rid of Mokichi so that he could be the most popular in Edo.
なんとか 茂吉を蹴落とし➡
江戸の人気を独占できねえかと
日々 模索してやがった｡
Before long, Mokichi's reputation began to wane. Gohei was behind this.
やがて いつからか
茂吉の評判が落ち始める｡
五兵衛の仕業よ｡
He pulled in all his connections and stuck Mokichi with all the worst jobs.
ﾔﾂは その広い人脈を利用し
裏で根回しして➡
茂吉に ﾛｸでもねえ仕事を
回していた｡
ﾑﾁｬで 難しい注文ばかり
押しつけられ➡
Mokichi had all the impossible and difficult jobs forced on him,
茂吉は 仕事が どんづまったのさ｡
and eventually, Mokichi was no longer able to find work.
五兵衛の企みどおりよ｡
Exactly as Gohei had planned.
Mokichi's popularity dwindled rapidly and Gohei's day had come...
茂吉の人気は みるみる下がり
五兵衛の天下がやってきた｡
Or so it seemed... But suddenly Mokichi's troubles just dissolved.
…かのように思われたが
それは すぐに去った｡
((五兵衛:えぇ!?))
Several years later, Mokichi's popularity surpassed that of Gohei's and
数年後には 茂吉の人気は
五兵衛を抜き➡
ﾔﾂは 江戸の頂点に立ったのさ｡
he was indisputably the top carpenter in Edo.
なんでか 気になるだろう？
You probably want to know why.
Gohei wanted to know, too.
当の五兵衛も そうさ！
You bastard, what kind of dirty trick did you pull?
((五兵衛:ｷｻﾏ いったい
どんな汚い手を使った？
ﾑﾁｬな仕事を押しつけられ➡
Weren't you getting forced to do all the impossible jobs?
どうにもならなく
なっていたではないか！))
茂吉は 言った｡
Mokichi replied...
You're right.
((茂吉:おぅ それよ｡
難しい仕事だったが➡
And it was difficult work, but it taught me more than I've ever known about carpentry.
おかげで 腕が
もうひとつ上がったよ｡
(茂吉)本当に ありがてえ話さ｡
うぅ…！))
I sure am grateful it happened.
茂吉 かっけぇ～！
茂吉さんは きっと➡
Mokichi's the bomb!
Mokichi probably didn't realize he was being tricked.
騙されたことにも
気づいてませんね それ｡
ただ 大工をすることが楽しくて
しかたなかったんだろうな｡
He loved carpentry so much that he welcomed the challenge!
職人ってよ…
そういうもんじゃねぇ？
Isn't that what it means to be a craftsman?
(２人)うっ…｡
Dammit!
(ｳﾝｹｲ)どﾁｸｼｮ～!!
That punk burns me up!
若造が ﾅﾏ言いやがって～！
Brother!! No matter how you look at it,
兄者～ ｵﾚたち どう考えても
踊らされてる！
they're playing us!
踊りまくらされてるよ～！
Like marionettes on a string!
わかってる わかってるけど
止まらねえ！
I know! I know, but I can't stop. He's got my carpenter's blood heated up!
大工の血が ｵﾚを駆り立てるんだ！
兄者～ ｵﾚもだ！
なんだ？ この気持｡
Brother! Me, too! What is this feeling?
茂吉も
こんな気持だったのか？
Was this how Mokichi felt?
Mokichi!!
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)茂吉～!!
誰？ 茂吉って｡
Who's Mokichi?
♪♪～
(小鳥の さえずり)
あぁ～…｡
How's that? You son of a bitch!
(ｳﾝｹｲ)どうだぁ！ この野郎！
(ｶｲｹｲ)これで文句ねえだろう！
You've got no complaints now!
見たか！
これが 宇宙一の大工の腕だ！
Witness the work of the greatest carpenters in the universe!
Wow! That's amazing. They even made a third floor, too.
うわぁ すごいや
ﾎﾝﾄに ３階もできてる！
私の部屋は 変わってないｱﾙ！
どういうことね！
My room hasn't changed at all! What's the meaning of this?
Wow, you two are pretty good.
やぁ なかなかやるじゃねえか｡
All right, then!
よ～し きたぁ！
じゃ ｵﾚたちは これで！
We'll be going now.
ねぇ！ 私の部屋は？
あとは 外だな｡
Hey, what about my room?
Well, there's still the outside.
Outside?
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)外～!?
(ｳﾝｹｲ)そ 外って 今さら➡
O-Outside? We already did the outside!
どうしろってんだよ！
(ｶｲｹｲ)なんで 今さら！
Yeah, you didn't say anything about that before!
最初に言えよ！
(神楽)おい！ 私の部屋は？
Hey, what about my room? Don't ignore me!
無視してんじゃねえぞ!!
No, but there's still something missing... The Odd Jobs was more...
やぁ やっぱさぁ
な～んか足んないんだよね｡
万事屋は もっとこう…｡
(２人)うわぁ!!
こんな感じだったような気がする｡
More like this...
おい～！ 足りないとか
そういう次元じゃないじゃん！
Hey, that is beyond missing something!
まるまる 違うじゃん！
That's totally different.
That's the Parthenon.
ﾊﾟﾙﾃﾉﾝじゃん！
そうだよ ﾊﾟﾌﾟﾍﾟﾎﾟﾝだよ｡
That's right. Like the "Parthemom."
ﾊﾟﾙﾃﾉﾝ
知んねえで言ってんのかい！
You showed us that without even knowing what the Parthenon is?!
そんなﾀﾞｻｲの や～よ！
That's lame!
It looked like this! This one!
こっちにしてよ こっち！
That's the Castle in the Sky!
[Note: "Castle in the Sky" is a popular anime film by Hayao Miyazaki.]
天空の城じゃねえか！ できるか！
いろんな意味で できるかぁ!!
That would be a trademark violation!!
もうﾑﾘだから！ もう帰るから！
This is pointless. We're leaving!
All right.
わかった｡
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)うん？
Okay, fine. You can leave it as is. Just make it fly.
じゃあ 形は
今のままでいいから➡
とりあえず 空飛ばせ この野郎｡
Make it so it flies when you push a button, you buttheads.
ﾎﾟﾁｯと押したら
飛ぶようにしとけ この野郎！
That's the biggest problem!
そこが いちばん問題なんだよ！
In what world have you ever seen a house that flies when you push a button?
どこの世界に ﾎﾟﾁｯと押したら
飛ぶ家があるんだよ！
Generally speaking, in the world of animation, when you push a button, things work out somehow.
だいたい ｱﾆﾒの世界じゃ
ﾎﾟﾁｯと押せば どうにかなるんだよ｡
That's right. All you do is just push a button for everything.
そうｱﾙ！ 何でも ﾎﾟﾁｯとなｱﾙ！
I'm getting tired of this.
もう つきあってらんねえ！
Really, we're leaving...
ﾎﾝﾄに 帰っからよ…｡
おい こんな話 知ってるか？
Hey, did you ever hear this story...?
(ｳﾝｹｲ)ちっくしょぉ～っ！
Dammit!!
若造が ﾅﾏ言いやがってぇ～！
That young punk's so annoying!
もう あの坂本とかいう男から
もらった金は➡
We already used up all the money that Sakamoto guy gave us a long time ago!!
とっくに尽きてるってのによぉ！
But still... What a shock that Mokichi had such a secret in his past!
まさか 茂吉に あんな謎が
隠されてるなんてよぉ！
Yeah, who can say no after hearing that!
あんなん聞かされたら
もう やるしかねえじゃねえか！
ｶｲｹｲ！ それは ｵﾚたちにも➡
Kaikei! That must mean we have the same heart as Mokichi.
茂吉と同じ心が
宿っているということだ！
そうなのか？ 兄者｡
ｵﾚたちも ﾔﾂと同じなのか？
You think so, Brother? We're the same as him?
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)茂吉～！
Mokichi!!
だから 茂吉って誰だよ？
Like I was saying, who is Mokichi?
Brother...it's already morning... Just a little bit more...
兄者… もう朝だ…
もうひと踏ん張りだぞ…｡
兄者？
少し休憩しよう…｡
Brother?
Let's take a break. I'll go get us some coffee.
ちょっくら ｺｰﾋｰでも
買ってきてやる｡
えっ…｡
根を詰めすぎても➡
You can't do good work by pushing yourself too hard.
いい仕事は できねえ…｡
Speed isn't everything.
早けりゃいいってもんじゃ
ねえだろうよ｡
But...
でもよぉ…｡
(ｳﾝｹｲ)茂吉だって➡
I'm sure Mokichi had a coffee or two
ｺｰﾋｰの １杯や２杯 飲みながら➡
ﾃﾒｴの仕事が完成していくのを
楽しんでいたはずだ｡
as he took pleasure in watching his work being completed.
While working, you reflect upon...
(ｳﾝｹｲ)仕事の楽しさを
かみしめながら やる｡
...the joy your work gives you.
職人ってよ…
そういうもんじゃねえか？
Isn't that what being a craftsman is all about?
兄者！ ｵﾚ 今 鳥肌たったぜ～!!
Brother! I just got goosebumps when I heard that!
ｶｲｹｲ！ ｵﾚたちが目指すは
ただ一つだ！
Kaikei! We have but one goal!
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)茂吉～！
Mokichi!!
で 何なんだよ 茂吉って？
So who is this Mokichi?
茂吉？ いねえよ そんなﾔﾂ｡
Mokichi? He doesn't exist.
ﾌｨｸｼｮﾝに 決まってんだろ｡
I just made him up.
ﾏｼﾞでか？
Are you serious?
Those two are so easy to fool.
簡単に騙されるもんなぁ…
ｱｲﾂら｡
でも そんなこと知ったら
あの２人 怒るでしょうね｡
But...if they ever find out, they'll be really mad.
I think it's best if we keep it to ourselves.
これは 内緒にしておいたほうが
いいですね｡
大丈夫だって あんな話
本気で信じるﾊﾞｶだぞ｡
Don't worry about it.
They're stupid enough to seriously buy into that story.
I'm sure they won't figure it out...
最後まで 気づくわけ…｡
You asshole! It was all a lie?! Shit...
ﾃﾒｴ… 全部 ｳｿだったのか！
ちょっ… 待て！
Hey, wait...
What?! Are you serious, Brother?
(ｶｲｹｲ)なんだと!? ﾎﾝﾄか 兄者！
You're saying Mokichi never existed?
茂吉なんて
いなかったっていうのか！
そうだ！ だから帰るぞ ｶｲｹｲ｡
That's right.
That's why we're leaving, Kaikei!
Our job is done here.
もう こんなところに用はねえ｡
(ｶｲｹｲ)しかし 兄者…｡
B-But, Brother!!
あぁ…｡
銀さん…｡
Gin-san...
Humph... Like I would ever come back to this planet again!
こんな星… 二度と来てたまるか！
でもよぉ 兄者…｡
But Brother... Was it okay to just leave in the middle of a job?
仕事を 途中で放り投げてきて
よかったのか…？
知るか！ ﾔﾂらは ｵﾚたちの心を
もてあそんだのに➡
Who cares? We worked hard for them and they toyed with our emotions.
ｵﾚたちは やるだけ
やってやったんだ！
They should be thankful.
感謝されるべきだろ！
そうかい｡
Oh yeah?
(ｶｲｹｲ)お前…｡
You...!
You got some nerve showing your face in front of us.
よくも ﾇｹﾇｹと
ｵﾚたちの前に姿を現せたな｡
Come on, don't say that... There must be some misunderstanding.
まぁ そう言うない…｡
ｵﾒｴら 何か
勘違いしてねえか？
なに!?
茂吉が いるか いねえかは➡
What?
Whether or not Mokichi existed is not the point.
問題じゃねえ…｡
That's totally irrelevant.
んなことは ﾊﾅから
どうでもいいことなんだ｡
What?!
なんだと？
どういうことだ？
What are you talking about?
The real Mokichi...
本当の茂吉はな…➡
ﾃﾒｴらみたいな 職人の魂ん中で
生きてんだよ！
...lives inside the souls of craftsmen like you guys...
Your faces already look like the face of Mokichi...
ｵﾒｴらの顔は もはや➡
茂吉のﾂﾗ構えに
なってきてんだよ…｡
Y...You...
お前…！
こんな話… 知ってるか？
Have you ever heard this story?
(泣き声)
I get it! I get it now!!
そうか！ そうだったのか!!
まさか茂吉の話に➡
Who knew there was such a mystery hidden behind the story of Mokichi.
あんな謎が
隠されてるなんてよぉ…！
Mokichi, you're the best!
茂吉ぃ！ 最高だぁ～!!
あんなん 聞かされたら…➡
Who can say no after hearing that?!
もう やるしかねえじゃねえか！
ｶｲｹｲ ｵﾚ… ﾜｹわかんねえよ！
Kaikei! I don't understand! Did Mokichi really exist or not?
本当に茂吉は
いるのか いないのか！
違うぞ 兄者！
すべて ｵﾚたちの魂なんだ！
It doesn't matter, Brother. It's all in our souls.
本当に いても いなくても➡
Whether he actually existed or not, Mokichi lives inside of us!
茂吉は ｵﾚたちの中で
生きてるんだ！
All right, Kaikei! Let's do this.
もういい ｶｲｹｲ！ やろう!!
Let's give it our all!
こうなったら とことんやろう！
Brother! Let's show them that we are the best carpenters in the universe!
兄者！ ｵﾚたちが 宇宙一の
大工であることを➡
思い知らせてやろう！
No! The second best! For the best must be...
(ｳﾝｹｲ)ｶｲｹｲ！ それは違う
ｵﾚたちは 宇宙で２番目だ！
(ｳﾝｹｲ)１番は…｡
(ｳﾝｹｲ/ｶｲｹｲ)茂吉ぃ～！
Mokichi!!
だから 茂吉って
誰だって 言ってんだろうが！
Like I said, who the heck is this Mokichi?
♪♪～
[Note: This is a parody of the Japanese show where celebrities visit various interesting sites around Japan]
[Atsunosuke Watanabe's Building Report]
[Tsuruya]
Good morning. I'm Atsunosuke Watanabe.
(渡辺)おはようございます
渡辺 篤之助です｡
今回は ここ 江戸の町の繁華街➡
Today, here in Kabukicho, Edo's business and shopping district,
かぶき町で 万事屋を営む
坂田 銀時さんの お宅に➡
we will be visiting the home of Gintoki Sakata who runs Odd Jobs.
おじゃましたいと思います｡
Oh, this must be his house.
あっ… この お宅ですね｡
(渡辺)今日の建物 坂田邸は➡
Today's building, the Sakata residence,
天人建築家
ｳﾝｹｲ ｶｲｹｲ兄弟の手で➡
was recently renovated by two Amanto architect brothers, Unkei and Kaikei,
先日 改築工事がなされました｡
(渡辺)ｷﾞﾘｼｬの ﾊﾟﾙﾃﾉﾝ神殿を
意識した外観と➡
The exterior is reminiscent of the Greek Parthenon
絢爛な宮殿部分を
融合させた 坂田邸を➡
and it is combined with a gorgeous palace section. I will now guide you through the Sakata residence.
ご案内いたします｡
では 早速 ご主人の坂田さんに
お話を伺いましょう｡
Let's talk to the master of the house, Sakata-san.
Hello...? Hmm...the doorbell is...
ごめんくだ… あれ？
ﾁｬｲﾑはっと… えぇっと…｡
Uh, let's see...
Is this it? Just push the button...
(渡辺)あっ これかな…
ﾎﾟﾁｯとな｡
♪♪～
I can feel a vibration...as profound as the exterior of the house.
外観どおりの 重厚な振動が
響いてきてますね｡
♪♪～
What a wonderful house. It flies!
空を飛べるなんて
ｽﾃｷな お宅ですねぇ…｡
♪♪～
Somebody...go get Mokichi...
誰か… 茂吉を呼んでこい…｡
[Preview]
Uh...what is wrong with me?
To have feelings for a girl other than Otsu-chan.
Cat ears... Cat ears are...
Super cute!!
The next episode: "Love Doesn't Require a Manual."
[The girl's name is "Eromesu." A beautiful girl with cute cat ears.]
[Note: Eromesu is a pun on Hermes, the Greek god.]
[Shinpachi has no experience in love and seeks help through the internet.]
[[Gin Tama, wouldn't it be fun to have a game like this? Or something like it?]
Gintama, wouldn't it be fun to have a game like this? Or something like it?
[What? Don't look at me.]
It's a Seaman-type game where you talk to an unemployed middle-aged man
[Note: Seaman is a virtual pet video game where you feed and care for "Seaman," a form of freshwater fish with a human like face, like a Sea Monkey.]
who is a DORK so you can help him get a job.
Basically, even if you start a conversation, the DORK (Dumb Old Retarded Kook) will ignore you.
That's because he already has his hands full with his own life.
He'll get depressed sometimes.
You may want to give him encouragement, but you must not talk to him.
You must never say to him "try your best."
Because he is already trying his best.
Sometimes, he'll try to play with a rope hanging from the ceiling.
When that happens, push the B button repeatedly to cut the rope.
Sometimes, he may just stare at the string hanging from the light and say "move...move."
[Butsu butsu]
When that happens, push the B button repeatedly as well.
[Good evening, I'm Betty.]
Sometimes, a strange woman may pay him a visit.
When that happens, shout "change" in a loud voice.
[Brain-rotting game DORK]
In the end, all you can say is "change."
(長谷川)ｼｰﾏﾝ的なﾏﾀﾞｵと
会話でｺﾐｭﾆｹｰｼｮﾝを図り➡
無職の彼が 仕事を見つけるまで
ｻﾎﾟｰﾄするｹﾞｰﾑだ｡
ﾏﾀﾞｵは基本 こちらから
しゃべりかけても 無視する｡
自分で いっぱい いっぱい
だからだ｡
たまに 落ち込むときがある｡
励ましたくなるが
しゃべりかけては いけない｡
｢がんばれ｣とか
絶対 言ってはいけない｡
なぜなら 彼は
すでに がんばっているからだ｡
たまに 天井から 紐をかけて
遊ぼうとするので➡
そんなときには Ｂﾎﾞﾀﾝを
連打して 紐を切ろう｡
たまに 電気についている
紐を 黙って見つめて➡
｢動け… 動け！｣と
言い出すときがある｡
そんなときも Ｂﾎﾞﾀﾝを連打しよう｡
たまに 変な女が
家に来ることがある｡
そんなときは 大きな声で
｢ﾁｪﾝｼﾞ！｣と 叫ぼう｡
結局 ｢ﾁｪﾝｼﾞ｣しか しゃべれねえ…｡